nationalobserver.com 2019-10-31

# Privacy policy | National Observer

At the NationalObserver.com we respect our readership and value personal privacy. We understand the nature of the information given to us and value the importance of protecting this information in accordance with the _Personal Information Protection Act_. 

All personal information submitted to the NationalObserver.com is kept confidential as described below and normally only viewed by the NationalObserver team. It is not sold or related to any other organization or company without prior consent. 

We do not disclose Personal Information to others, without first, attempting to notify you. 

We take reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information. 

We maintain reasonably physical, technical, and procedural measures to limit access to Personal Information to authorized individuals with appropriate purposes and protocols. As set out in our terms of use, we will endeavour to notify you first but reserve the right to disclose any information necessary to satisfy legal requirement, regulation, and government request or to preserve our rights. 

We manage subscriptions with a third party service called Piano Essentials. Piano has their own privacy policy that you can read at [http://piano.io./privacy](http://piano.io./privacy). Subscription payments are processed by[ Braintree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/en-ca?locale=en-ca).

We use cookies to identify your individual browser and to assist in the site’s operation. No personally identifiable information is collected via cookies. Some cookies are only saved while you’re using the site, and others assist you while you have left the site. If you have disabled cookies through your browser, some site functions may not work properly. 

One of the third party services we use, Google Analytics, also uses cookies. To opt out of Google Analytics and related marketing services, follow the steps outlined[ here. ](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

Despite our best efforts, a data breach is possible. In the event of a data breach coming to our attention, whether or not through our fault, we will immediately notify all persons whose Personal Information has been or may have been inappropriately hacked or disclosed, we will minimize the breach and we will take steps to minimize foreseeable damage in the circumstances. We will keep those potentially affected abreast of our investigation and steps to mitigate damage. 

The policy may be revised or updated at any time and we encourage you to check back often to ensure that you are familiar with the most recent version and the terms of our policy. 

If you have any questions related to our Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://www.nationalobserver.com/contact).
